

### Evgenii Kotelnikov, Ph.D.

Date of birth: 15 February 1990

**Current location:** Gothenburg, Sweden (open to relocation)

I am a software developer and a computer scientist dedicated to improving the quality of software

through the use of static analysis, formal verification, functional programming and advanced type systems.

My academic background is a Ph.D. in Computer Science on the topic of automated theorem proving.

Over the last 15 years I have worked as a software developer within Cloud, Web, Telecom and Automotive.

I have worked with several different tech stacks, my preferred day-to-day ones are C, Python, Scala and Haskell.

# Work experience

#### in My LinkedIn profile

February 2021 to now 🛗

Gothenburg, Sweden 9

#### Zenseact AB

Software developer

Zenseact develops an autonomous driving platform for Volvo Cars.

- Develop safety critical software components of self-driving cars in C, C++ and Ada.
- · Scout for requirements, breakdown, refine and formalize.
- Integrate the SPARK verification toolchain into the company's codebase. Formally verify safety requirements of the core components in SPARK.
- C++ Python Ada **SPARK**

#### **Ericsson AB**

August 2019 to January 2021 ## Gothenburg, Sweden 9

Software developer Implemented new features for the control plane of SGSN-MME in Erlang.

- Helped to migrate Ericsson's 5G platform from custom hardware to the telco cloud. Among other things, implemented a
- cloud-based storage and logging infrastructure for it. Linux Erlang Bash Python Kubernetes Docker

Chalmers University of Technology

September 2013 to September 2018 ## Gothenburg, Sweden 9

Doctoral researcher Conducted research in the areas of automated theorem proving, formal methods and functional programming.

- Published and presented academic results in conferences and workshops (see my Google Scholar profile).
- Actively contributed to Vampire, a state-of-the-art automated theorem prover for first-order logic.
- Assisted to preparing assignments, conducting consultation sessions and grading exams in the courses on Functional Programming, Databases, Algorithms and Datastructures.
- approx. 1000 students and 20 faculty members. Java Haskell Python PostgreSQL Oracle Database

• Developed and maintained a homework submission system in the Computer Science department used annually by

**Amazon Web Services** 

March 2017 to June 2017 ## New York, USA 9

Applied scientist intern, Automated Reasoning Group Implemented an experimental backend for Tiros — a static analyzer of AWS virtual private cloud networks.

Python Datalog Scala Vampire **Z**3

Yandex Inc.

March 2011 to August 2013 ## Saint-Petersburg, Russia 9

Software developer • Developed the back end of high-load web search services, including an in-house performant database solution

capable of serving up to 400 requests per second.

Redis

- Developed information retrieval tools and web crawlers. Developed an app recommendation system for Yandex.Store.
- Java Scala Akka Oracle Database MongoDB

July 2010 to December 2010 ##

Software engineering intern Designed a specification language for low-level telecom protocols and implemented a toolchain for it.

Motorola Solutions Inc.

Saint-Petersburg, Russia 9

С Python Wireshark Lisp

**Freelance** 

Remote ♀

2005 to 2010 mm

PHP MySQL **HTML** CSS **JavaScript jQuery** 

Developed front end and back end of commercial websites.

### Doctor of philosophy (Ph.D.)

**Education** 

Web developer

## Thesis titled "Automated Theorem Proving with Extensions of First-Order Logic"

Automated theorem proving

September 2013 to September 2018 🛗

Gothenburg, Sweden 9

Ph.D. supervisors Laura Kovács and Andrei Voronkov

Chalmers University of Technology, Department of Computer Science

in. The applications include automation of proof assistants and static analysis of software and networks. First-order logic Formal methods Static analysis Vampire

Master of science (M.Sc.) September 2011 to July 2013 🛗

Saint-Petersburg State University, Department of Applied Mathematics Saint-Petersburg, Russia 9

Metaprogramming Monads Computational effects Scala

Explored ways to make automated theorem provers more efficient for applications by extending the logic that they reason

Bachelor of science (B.Sc.) Saint-Petersburg State University, Department of Applied Mathematics

Saint-Petersburg, Russia 9

My GitHub profile

September 2007 to July 2011 🛗

Thesis titled "Source Code Generation Based on Language Grammar Description" Source code generation Context-free grammars Algebraic data types

Thesis titled "Syntactical Extensions of Scala for Effectful Computations"

### Public software projects

Scala

An award-winning automated theorem prover A verification conditions generator for the Boogie

> intermediate verification language. atomizer Erlang

Haskell

Scheme

An extension to Scala for boilerplate-free syntax for effectful A static analysis tool for finding loose atoms in large Erlang code bases. computations.

atp Haskell fire Python **HTML** CoffeeScript Docker

vampire C++

for first-order logic.

scala-workflow

voogie

Haskell interface to automated theorem provers. A submission system for homework assignments.